Andrei R. Rabon

Zamboanga City, Zamboanga del Sur, Philippines • +63 927-158-0043 andreirabon@gmail.com • GitHub • Portfolio

Summary

React-focused Frontend Web Developer with three years of Quality Assurance experience. Leveraging quality assurance background to build efficient and effective web applications.

Skills

Technical: Git, Figma, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, REST API, Tailwind CSS, React, Next.js, Vitest, Jira, Project Management, and Personnel Administration.

Interests: Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, Python, Go, Development Operations (DevOps), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, and Google Cloud.

Experience

1. AKA Software Inc.Zamboanga CityLead Quality Assurance TesterJanuary 2022 – Present

- Found and reported website bugs using both manual and automated tests with Playwright.
- Tracked issues in Jira and created documentation in Confluence.

2. Philippine Statistics Authority RFO 9

Zamboanga City

Data Map Screener

August - October 2021

Updated geotagged building structure data and geotagged economic data using QGIS.

3. Department of Agriculture RFO 9

Zamboanga City

Administrative Aide III

January – December 2020

- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap to create frontend web page drafts.
- Supported the ICT Planning Monitoring and Evaluation Division by handling administrative tasks (phone calls, emails, data entry) and providing technical support for computer hardware and software.

4. Department of Information and Communications Technology RFO 9 Internship

Zamboanga City

November 2018 – January 2019

• Assisted the Tech4Ed team with launching a new center and promoting the program through school and community outreach; supported the eBPLS team by preparing and facilitating seminars and workshops.

Education

Undergraduate: Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Pilar College

Zamboanga City, Zamboanga del Sur

2016 - 2019

Postgraduate: Master of Public Administration Major in Personnel Administration

Western Mindanao State University Zamboanga City, Zamboanga del Sur

2021 - 2024 (CAR)